http://www.protective.com/privacy-policy

Skip to Content
Privacy policiesLast updated July 10, 2020
The Protective Privacy Center provides you with information about privacy policies and practices applicable to Protective’s life insurance and asset protection subsidiaries. We use the terms “Protective,” “we,” “us,” and “our” to refer to these subsidiaries and our parent company, Protective Life Corporation. If you have questions about our privacy policies and practices, please e-mail privacycenter@protective.com.
Privacy Notices for Protective CustomersIf you are a Protective customer, our Customer Privacy Policy applies to any personal information that you share with us. A Protective customer is an individual who is the policyholder on contract holder of a Protective product or to whom Protective otherwise provides products or services. Our Customer Privacy Policy applies to former customers in the same way it applies to current customers. select the version of our Customer Privacy Policy that applies to you.
If you are a Zurich American Life Insurance Company Customer whose policy is administered by Protective, read the privacy notice that applies to your policy.
Online Privacy PolicyThis Online Privacy Policy applies to all websites owned and/or operated by Protective that link to this Online Privacy Policy.
Protective recognizes that protecting the privacy and security of personal information is an important responsibility. This Online Privacy Policy tells you how we treat personal information that we collect when you use the website from which you are accessing this Online Privacy Policy and the measures we take to safeguard that information.Using Our Websites and Sharing Personal Information with Us
We provide online tools and resources that allow you to share personal information with us. Those tools and resources are designed to use personal information so that we can give you a personalized response to an inquiry, or provide you with information about services and products that may meet your needs.
When you share personal information with us for these purposes, we may share that information with our affiliates, or with other companies who help us respond to your questions or market our own products to you. We will not share personal information with anyone else unless we have your permission, or we are allowed or required by law to disclose it.
How We Safeguard Personal InformationWe seek to maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect personal information within our organization.
Other Information We Receive from Visitors to Our Websites
We may collect other information—which is information that does not reveal your specific identity or relate to an identifiable individual—in a variety of ways, including:
Through your browser or device:
Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, and Internet browser type and version. We use this information to ensure that our websites function properly.
Using cookies:
Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the computer that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on our websites, pages visited, language preferences, and other traffic data. We use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, to personalize your experience while using the websites, and to recognize your computer in order to assist your use of the websites.
We also gather statistical information about use of the websites in order to continually improve their design and functionality, understand how they are used and assist us with resolving questions regarding them. We may also use cookies or other technologies to track responses to our online advertisements.
If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies or be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer to your computer of a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. You may also wish to refer to www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of our websites. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer, and you may need to log in every time you visit.
Using pixel tags and other similar technologies:
Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used in connection with our websites to, among other things, track the actions of users (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns, and compile statistics about use of the websites and response rates.
We do not respond to browser do-not-track signals at this time.
Analytics:
We use certain analytics services, which use cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the websites and report on activities and trends.
You can learn about our service provider Google’s analytics practices by going to www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/, and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
This site uses the Lucky Orange analytics system to help improve usability and the customer experience. Lucky Orange may record mouse clicks, mouse movements and scrolling activity. Lucky Orange may record keystroke information that you voluntarily enter on this website. Lucky Orange does not track this activity on any site that does not use the Lucky Orange system. You can choose to disable the Lucky Orange Service at www.luckyorange.com/disable.php. Note that doing so will disable other features of the Lucky Orange system that this site employs such as 1-to-1 support chat.
Using Adobe Flash technology:
We may use Adobe Flash Local Shared Objects (“Flash LSOs”) to, among other things, collect and store information about your use of the websites. You can control Flash LSOs by going to the Global Storage Settings Panel on the Macromedia site.
IP Address:
Your IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider. An IP address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses our website, along with the time of the visit and the pages visited. Collecting IP addresses is standard practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications, and other services. We use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating use levels, diagnosing server problems, and administering the websites. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP address.
We may use and disclose the other information described above for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we combine such information with personal information, we will treat the combined information as personal information.Our AdvertisingWe may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements regarding products and services that may be of interest to you when you access and use our websites and applications, and other websites and online services, based on information relating to your access to and use of any such services on any of your devices, as well as on information received from third parties. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through the use of pixel tags).
They may also use these technologies, along with information they collect about your online use, to recognize you across the devices you use, such as a mobile phone and a laptop. If you would like more information about this practice, and to learn how to opt out of it in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Online Privacy Policy, please visit www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp and www.aboutads.info/.
Our online advertising practices are designed to comply with the Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.
Keeping Up To Date with our Online Privacy PolicyWe have the right to change our Online Privacy Policy. If we make a material change to this policy or our information collection practices, we will notify you in accordance with applicable law.
CCPA Privacy PolicyThe following disclosures are made pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”). These disclosures supplement any privacy notices we previously or contemporaneously provided to you. The below chart reflects the categories of personal information we have collected from California consumers over the past twelve months, the categories of sources from which the information was collected, the business or commercial purpose for which the information was collected, and the categories of third parties with whom we shared that information.
Please click on each category below to view the sources of collection, business/commercial purpose for collection, and categories of third parties receiving personal information.Personal identifiers including your name, alias, signature, address, phone number, email address, social security number, driver’s license or other state identification card number, passport number, or any other personal identifier.
Sources of Collection
You
Paramedical Examiners
A Policyholder
Affiliates
Distributors
Insurance Support Organizations
Consumer Reporting Agencies
Consumer Marketing Companies
Auto Dealerships
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Marketing Partners
Underwriting Services
Insurance Support Organizations
Clearing Agencies
Service Providers
Physical characteristics or description including age, height, weight, gender, gender identity, or gender expression.
Sources of Collection
You
Paramedical Examiners
A Policyholder
Affiliates
Distributors
Insurance Support Organizations
Consumer Reporting Agencies
Consumer Marketing Companies
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Marketing Partners
Underwriting Services
Insurance Support Organizations
Service Providers
Other personal information such as your national origin, marital status, or parental status.
Sources of Collection
You
A Policyholder
Affiliates
Distributors
Insurance Support Organizations
Consumer Reporting Agencies
Consumer Marketing Companies
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Marketing Partners
Underwriting Services
Insurance Support Organizations
Service Providers
Financial information including your bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or other financial information.
Sources of Collection
You
Affiliates
Distributors
Auto Dealerships
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Service Providers
Education and employment information including your citizenship, and current and prior employment.
Sources of Collection
You
A policyholder
Affiliates
Distributors
Insurance Support Organizations
Consumer Reporting Agencies
Consumer Marketing Companies
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Marketing Partners
Underwriting Services
Insurance Support Organizations
Service Providers
Insurance information including policy and coverage information for auto, boat, health, disability, life, home, renters, long-term care, or other personal insurance.
Sources of Collection
You
A policyholder
Affiliates
Distributors
Insurance Support Organizations
Consumer Reporting Agencies
Consumer Marketing Companies
Auto Dealerships
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Marketing Partners
Underwriting Services
Insurance Support Organizations
Service Providers
Medical information including medical conditions, physical disability, mental disability, pregnancy or childbirth, or genetic information.
Sources of Collection
You
Paramedical Examiners
A policyholder
Affiliates
Distributors
Insurance Support Organizations
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Underwriting Services
Insurance Support Organizations
Service Providers
Internet and other network activity information including online identifiers such as your IP address or device identifier, browsing history, search history, and information about your interactions with websites, applications, or advertisements.
Sources of Collection
You
Consumer Marketing Companies
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
To assess and improve the performance of our websites and other online services.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Consumer Marketing Companies
Analytics Providers
Service Providers
Purchasing history and tendencies including records of personal property, products, or services purchased, obtained, or considered.
Sources of Collection
You
Consumer Reporting Agencies
Consumer Marketing Companies
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Marketing Partners
Service Providers
Photographs, video recordings, or audio recordings.
Sources of Collection
You
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Information reflecting your preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitude, intelligence, ability, aptitude, and any other inferences drawn from your personal information.
Sources of Collection
You
Consumer Reporting Agencies
Consumer Marketing Companies
Business/Commercial Purpose for Collection
To provide you with our products and services.
To provide you with information that may help you to determine your financial and insurance needs.
To respond to your questions.
Categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
Affiliates
Distributors
Marketing Partners
Service Providers
In the past twelve months, we have disclosed personal information to third parties for business or commercial purposes. The categories of personal information we have disclosed to third parties for business or commercial purposes are:
Personal identifiers
Physical characteristics
National origin, marital status, or parental status
Financial information
Education and employment information
Insurance information
Medical information
Internet and other network activity information
Purchasing history and tendencies
Inferences drawn from your personal information
In the past twelve months we have not sold personal information to third parties.
Right to Opt Out
California residents have the right to opt out of the sale of their personal information. As of the last updated date of this Policy, Protective does not sell personal information, However, Protective provides an opt-out process so that if Protective decides to sell personal information in the future, your opt-out choice can be applied to your personal information. You or your authorized agent can submit an online opt out request or by calling 1-844-908-1164.
Right to Know
California residents have the right to request that we disclose the categories and specific pieces of personal information we collected, used, disclosed, and sold during the past twelve months, the categories of sources from which their personal information was collected, our business or commercial purposes for collecting their personal information, and the categories of third parties with whom we shared their personal information. You can submit an online request or by calling 1-844-908-1164. The personal information that we use to verify your identity will not be used for any other purpose.
Right to Delete
California residents have the right to request deletion of the personal information we have collected from them. You can submit an online deletion request or by calling 1-844-908-1164. The personal information that we use to verify your identity will not be used for any other purpose.
In order to verify your Right to Opt Out, Right to Know, or Right to Delete request, we will use the information you provide in making the request and, as necessary and/or appropriate, information available from third party verification tools.
We do not discriminate against California residents who exercise their CCPA privacy rights.
As of the last updated date of this Policy, we do not sell the personal information of minors under 16 years of age.
For California Consumers of Protective Life Asset Protection Division: An accessible version of point of sale notice for purchase of service contract, ancillary product, or guaranteed asset protection product.
